Chapter 21. Going aboard.
It was nearly 6:00, but only gray, imperfect, misty dawn when we drew nigh
the warp. There are some sailors running ahead there, if I see right, said I to
Quiqu. It can't be shadows. She's off by sunrise, I guess. Come on. Avast," cried
a voice, whose owner, at the same time coming close behind us, laid a hand upon
both our shoulders, and then, insinuating himself between us, stood
stooping forward a little, in the uncertain twilight, strangely peering
from Queig to me. It was Elijah. "Going aboard?" "Hands off, will you?" said I.
"Lookie here," said Quequ, shaking himself. "Go away." "Ain't going then."
"Yes, we are," said I. But what business is that of yours? Do you know, Mr.
Elijah, that I consider you a little impertinent? No, no, no, I wasn't aware
of that, said Elijah, slowly and wonderingly, looking for me to Quiquake
with the most unaccountable glances.
Elijah, said I. You will oblige my friend and me by withdrawing. We are
going to the Indian and Pacific oceans, and would prefer not to be detained. You
be coming back before breakfast? He's cracked, Quiqu said I. Come on. Hello,
cried stationary Elijah, hailing us when we had removed a few paces. Never mind
him, said I. Quiquague, come on. But he stole up to us again, and suddenly
clapping his hands on my shoulder, said, "Did you see anything looking like men
going towards that ship a while ago?"
Struck by this plain matter-of-fact question, I answered, saying, "Yes, I
thought I did see four or five men, but it was too dim to be sure." "Very dim!
Very dim," said Elijah. "Morning to you." Once more we quitted him, but once
more he came softly after us, and touching my shoulder again, said, "See
if you can find him now, will you?"
"Find who? Morning to you. Morning to you, he rejoined again, moving off. Oh,
I was going to warn you against But never mind. Never mind. It's all one.
All in the family, too. Sharp frost this morning, ain't it? Goodbye to you. Shant
see you again very soon, I guess, unless it's before the grand jury. And with
these cracked words, he finally departed, leaving me for the moment in
no small wonderment at his frantic impedance.
At last, stepping on board the Peekquad, we found everything in profound quiet,
not a soul moving. The cabin entrance was locked within, the hatches were all
on, and lumbered with coils of rigging.
Going forward to the folks, we found the slide of the scuttle open. Seeing a
light, we went down, and found only an old rigger there, wrapped in a tattered
pea jacket. He was thrown at whole length upon two chests, his face
downwards, and enclosed in his folded arms. The profoundest slumber slept upon
him. "Those sailors we saw," Quiquake, where can they have gone to? Said I,
looking dubiously at the sleeper. "But it seemed that when on the warf,
Quiquake had not at all noticed what I now alluded to. Hence I would have
thought myself to have been optically deceived in that matter, were it not for
Elijah's otherwise inexplicable question. But I beat the thing down, and
again, marking the sleeper, jocularly hinted to Quiquake that perhaps we had
best sit up with the body, telling him to establish himself accordingly. He put
his hand upon the sleeper's rear as though feeling if it was soft enough,
and then, without morue, quietly sat down there. "Gracious, Quiqu, don't sit
there," said I. "Oh, perid seat," said Quequ. "My country won't hurt him." Face
face said I called that his face. A very benevolent countenance then. But how
hard he breathes. He's heaving himself.
Get off Quiquake. You're heavy. It's grinding the face of the poor. Get off
Quiqu Quag. Look, he'll twitch you off soon. I wonder he don't wake. Quiquag
removed himself to just beyond the head of the sleeper and lighted his tomahawk
pipe. I sat at the feet. We kept the pipe passing over the sleeper and from
one to the other. Meanwhile, upon questioning him in his broken fashion,
Quiquay gave me to understand that in his land, owing to the absence of setis
and sofas of all sorts, the kings, chiefs, and great people generally were
in the custom of fattening some of the lower orders for Ottomans. And to
furnish a house comfortably in that respect, you had only to buy up eight or
10 lazy fellows and lay them round in the peers and ales. Besides, it was very
convenient on an excursion, much better than those garden chairs, which are
convertible into walking sticks. Upon occasion, a chief calling his attendant,
and desiring him to make a seti of himself under a spreading tea, perhaps
in some damp marshy place. While narrating these things, every time
Quiquake received the tomahawk from me, he flourished the hatchet side of it
over the sleeper's head. What's that for, Quiqu?
Perry, easy, killy. Oh, Perry, easy. He was going on with some wild
reminiscences about his tomahawk pipe, which it seemed had, in its two uses,
both brained his foes and soothed his soul, when we were directly attracted to
the sleeping rigger. The strong vapor was now completely filling the
contracted hole. It began to tell upon him. He breathed with a sort of
muffledness, then seemed troubled in the nose, then revolved over once or twice,
then sat up and rubbed his eyes.
Hello, he breathed at last. Who be you smokers? Shipped men answered I. When
does she sail? I I You're going in her be? She sails today. The captain came
aboard last night. What captain? Ahab.
Who? But him indeed. I was going to ask him some further questions concerning
Ahab when we heard a noise on deck.
Hello Starbucks a stir said the rigger he's a lively chief mate that good man
and a pious but all alive now I must turn two and so saying he went on deck
and we followed. It was now clear sunrise. Soon the crew came on board in
twos and threes. The riggers burred themselves. The mates were actively
engaged, and several of the shore people were busy in bringing various last
things on board. Meanwhile, Captain Ahab remained invisibly enshrined within his cabin.